# **CARSON JAMES**

(704) 682-3501 ■ tarheelkid44@yahoo.com ■ 157 Sundance Circle, Statesville, NC 28625

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am a highly motivated, goal-oriented, and passionate college graduate determined to make a difference. I thrive to work hard and set objectives for myself and the betterment of my career. My goal is to build my portfolio with experiences that develop my skillset and allow me to provide value to my company and team members.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Account Sales Representative - Cellular Sales

Statesville, NC *June 2021 - Present* 

- Exceed monthly sales goals each month. Over the last 2 years I was able to attain my monthly goal of \$3500. For 23 of those 24 months, I exceeded my goals by 140%-200%, coming in at \$5000-\$7000 in monthly sales.
- Specialized in phone sales and account analysis for a subsidiary of Verizon through the indirect retailer. Working on the consumer and business sides allowed me to interact with large amounts of customers and connect with businesses such as Potts, Combs, Rhyne, & Teague, an accounting firm in Statesville, NC.
- Trained newly hired sales team members regarding company procedures, standards, and products.
- Attended scheduled training sessions, department meetings, and company events to build expertise and promote company image.
- Sales region was limited to my store. However, boasted the opportunity to move around to different regions to aid in the development of many underdeveloped regions within the state. Traveling exposed me to different customers and client relations of those regions, as well as the different practices, tendencies, and cultures within said regions.
- Called and met with regular and prospective customers to build long-term customer relationships and networks. Through account analysis and relationships with my current customer base, like my business account for the KOA Campground out of Union Grove, allowed me to network with other businesses from Australia that needed their account managed while residing in the States.
- Negotiated contracts and pricing with clients to exceed sales goals consistently by a 140%-200% margin to achieve the extra \$2000-\$3000 extra in monthly sales over the set goal of \$3500.
- Remained current on relevant products, industry, and sales tactic information to provide up-to-date pricing and services to my customer base.
- Developed and maintained strong customer relationships and networks within designated sales region.
- Highlighted new products and company promotions during sales blitz.
- Used knowledge of company products and services to recommend solutions to customers.

#### **Groundskeeper - Statesville Country Club**

Statesville, NC Summers of 2018 - 2020 [Part Time]

- I was responsible for the upkeep of the country clubs golf course. My jobs included weed-eating, mowed, edged, trimmed bushes, and did slight concrete and hard scapes (mulching, cutting down trees, and overall movement of dirt for new and improved areas of the course.
- One thing that I enjoyed as apart of the everyday life was the interactions and connections I made with members and guest of the country club. As they would pass through on the job I loved the conversations with the different businessmen, doctors, and people of all walks of life. To create connections with people like like those members and previous employer, Shane Harrelson, whom I could go to to this day. That allowed for great personable relationships in the clubhouse and overall made doing jobs around the course more enjoyable and interactive.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN EXERCISE SCIENCE

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC

GPA: 3.4

**AA IN ARTS** 

Surry Community College, Dobson, NC

August 2019—May 2021

August 2017—May 2019

FULL STACK CODING BOOTCAMP

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

March 2023—Present

### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Account Analysis
- Goal-oriented
- Personable
- Hardworking
- Attentive to details

- Highly motivated
- Adaptable
- Quick learner
- Sports Coaching
- Full Stack Coding

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Cars and Coffee
- Playing Sports ie: Golf and Baseball
- Sports Memorabilia
- Coding and Technology

- Spending quality time with Family
- Traveling & Site-seeing
- Creating lifelong personal relationships through my career and personal life.